<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- RelStorage configuration via ZConfig -->

<component prefix="relstorage.config">

  <import package="ZODB"/>
  <abstracttype name="relstorage.adapter"/>

  <sectiontype name="relstorage" implements="ZODB.storage"
      datatype=".RelStorageFactory">
    <section type="relstorage.adapter" name="*" attribute="adapter"/>
    <key name="name" datatype="string" required="no"/>
    <key name="create" datatype="boolean" default="true">
      <description>
        Flag that indicates whether the storage should be initialized if
        it does not already exist.
      </description>
    </key>
    <key name="read-only" datatype="boolean" default="false">
      <description>
        If true, only reads may be executed against the storage.  Note
        that the "pack" operation is not considered a write operation
        and is still allowed on a read-only filestorage.
      </description>
    </key>
    <key name="poll-interval" datatype="float" required="no">
      <description>
        Defer polling the database for the specified maximum time interval.
        Set to 0 (the default) to always poll.  Fractional seconds are
        allowed.

        Use this to lighten the database load on servers with high read
        volume and low write volume.  A setting of 1-5 seconds is sufficient
        for most systems.

        While this setting should not affect database integrity,
        it increases the probability of basing transactions on stale data,
        leading to conflicts.  Thus a nonzero setting can hurt
        the performance of servers with high write volume.
      </description>
    </key>
    <key name="pack-gc" datatype="boolean" default="true">
      <description>
        If pack-gc is false, pack operations do not perform
        garbage collection.  Garbage collection is enabled by default.

        If garbage collection is disabled, pack operations keep at least one
        revision of every object.  With garbage collection disabled, the
        pack code does not need to follow object references, making
        packing conceivably much faster.  However, some of that benefit
        may be lost due to an ever increasing number of unused objects.

        Disabling garbage collection is also a hack that ensures
        inter-database references never break.
      </description>
    </key>
    <key name="pack-batch-timeout" datatype="float" required="no">
      <description>
        Packing occurs in batches of transactions; this specifies the
        timeout in seconds for each batch.  Note that some database
        configurations have unpredictable I/O performance
        and might stall much longer than the timeout.
        The default timeout is 5.0 seconds.
      </description>
    </key>
    <key name="pack-duty-cycle" datatype="float" required="no">
      <description>
        After each batch, the pack code pauses for a time to
        allow concurrent transactions to commit.  The pack-duty-cycle
        specifies what fraction of time should be spent on packing.
        For example, if the duty cycle is 0.75, then 75% of the time
        will be spent packing: a 6 second pack batch
        will be followed by a 2 second delay.  The duty cycle should
        be greater than 0.0 and less than or equal to 1.0.  Specify
        1.0 for no delay between batches.

        The default is 0.5.  Raise it to finish packing faster; lower it
        to reduce the effect of packing on transaction commit performance.
      </description>
    </key>
    <key name="pack-max-delay" datatype="float" required="no">
      <description>
        This specifies a maximum delay between pack batches.  Sometimes
        the database takes an extra long time to finish a pack batch; at
        those times it is useful to cap the delay imposed by the
        pack-duty-cycle.  The default is 20 seconds.
      </description>
    </key>
    <key name="cache-servers" datatype="string" required="no">
      <description>
        Specifies a list of memcache servers.  Enabling memcache integration
        is useful if the connection to the relational database has high
        latency and the connection to memcache has significantly lower
        latency.  On the other hand, if the connection to the relational
        database already has low latency, memcache integration may actually
        hurt overall performance.

        Provide a list of host:port pairs, separated by whitespace.
        "127.0.0.1:11211" is a common setting.  The default is to disable
        memcache integration.
      </description>
    </key>
    <key name="cache-module-name" datatype="string" required="no">
      <description>
        Specifies which Python memcache module to use.  The default is
        "memcache", a pure Python module.  An alternative module is
        "cmemcache".  This setting has no effect unless cache-servers is set.
      </description>
    </key>
  </sectiontype>

  <sectiontype name="postgresql" implements="relstorage.adapter"
    datatype=".PostgreSQLAdapterFactory">
    <key name="dsn" datatype="string" required="no" default="">
      <description>
        The PostgreSQL data source name.  For example:

        dsn dbname='template1' user='user' host='localhost' password='pass'

        If dsn is omitted, the adapter will connect to a local database with
        no password.  Both the user and database name will match the
        name of the owner of the current process.
      </description>
    </key>
  </sectiontype>

  <sectiontype name="oracle" implements="relstorage.adapter"
    datatype=".OracleAdapterFactory">
    <key name="user" datatype="string" required="yes">
      <description>
        The Oracle account name
      </description>
    </key>
    <key name="password" datatype="string" required="yes">
      <description>
        The Oracle account password
      </description>
    </key>
    <key name="dsn" datatype="string" required="yes">
      <description>
        The Oracle data source name.  The Oracle client library will
        normally expect to find the DSN in /etc/oratab.
      </description>
    </key>
  </sectiontype>

  <sectiontype name="mysql" implements="relstorage.adapter"
    datatype=".MySQLAdapterFactory">

    <key name="host" datatype="string" required="no">
      <description>
        host to connect
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name="user" datatype="string" required="no">
      <description>
        user to connect as
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name="passwd" datatype="string" required="no">
      <description>
        password to use
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name="db" datatype="string" required="no">
      <description>
        database to use
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name="port" datatype="integer" required="no">
      <description>
        TCP/IP port to connect to
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name="unix_socket" datatype="string" required="no">
      <description>
        location of unix_socket (UNIX-ish only)
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name="connect_timeout" datatype="integer" required="no">
      <description>
        number of seconds to wait before the connection attempt fails.
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name="compress" datatype="boolean" required="no">
      <description>
        if set, gzip compression is enabled
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name="named_pipe" datatype="boolean" required="no">
      <description>
        if set, connect to server via named pipe (Windows only)
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name="read_default_file" datatype="string" required="no">
      <description>
        see the MySQL documentation for mysql_options()
      </description>
    </key>

    <key name="read_default_group" datatype="string" required="no">
      <description>
        see the MySQL documentation for mysql_options()
      </description>
    </key>

  </sectiontype>

</component>
